Finding Aid for Robert E. Cole Papers, 1982-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robert E. Cole Papers 1982-1984
Cole, Robert E.
1.5 linear ft.
Director of the Center for Japanese Studies at the University of Michigan; co-head with Keiichi Oshima of the Joint United States/Japanese Automotive Study. Background files; reports; and records relating to meetings, surveys, and fieldwork of the joint study.
88406 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Robert E. Cole (donor no. 6783 ) and came to the library June-July 1988.
The collection is open for research.
In 1982, Robert Cole, director of the Center for Japanese Studies at the University of Michigan, began work on a two-year study comparing the United States and Japanese automotive industries. Cole, along with Keiichi Oshima (University of Tokyo and vice-chairman of the research firm Technova, Inc.), headed the Joint United States/Japanese project formed out of a concern for the health of international trade and Japanese relations.
The Cole Papers consist of the records of the study comparing the United States and Japanese automotive industries. The collection is arranged under three broad headings: Background; Meetings, Surveys, and Field; and Reports of Study. Included are the final reports, working paper series (22 individual research projects), progress reports, interviews, surveys, meeting minutes, and materials relating to the structure and composition of the study. The collection also includes the published volume resulting from the study.
Subjects:
Automobile industry and trade--Japan.; Automobile industry and trade--United States.; Japan--Study and teaching--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Center for Japanese Studies.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Contributors:
Oshima, Keiichi, 1921-
- Background
  - Proposal (Box 1)
  - Study Overview and Outline (Box 1)
  - Confidential Policy (Box 1)
  - Classification of Companies (Box 1)
  - Contacts, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Funding-Second Year (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
- Meetings, Surveys, and Fieldwork
  - Interim Report and Meetings, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Trade Framework Meetings, April 1983 (Box 1)
  - Minutes-Policy Board Meeting, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Meetings (Box 1)
  - Sound Recordings of Meetings (Box 1)
  - Survey
    - Statements On (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Versions (Box 1)
    - Semi-Final Versions, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Sample (Box 1)
    - Costs (Box 1)
  - Fieldwork
    - Proposed Interview Questions (Box 1)
    - Case Studies, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Interviews (Box 1)
    - Reports of Meetings with Japanese Companies (Box 1)
- Reports of Study
  - Reports (Box 2)
  - Progress Reports, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Reports-Japanese side, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Working Paper Series 1-22, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Final Reports, 1984, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Press Coverage, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Book: The American and Japanese Auto Industries in Transition edited by Robert E. Cole and Taizo Yakushiji (1984) (Box 2)